# **Syed Anas Ahmed**

Chennai, India | +91 8932916589

syedanas2607@gmail.com | https://syedanas.com/

Highly motivated and experienced computer science engineer with over 2 years of experience in software development, full-stack development, and web development. Strong technical skills in multiple programming languages and experience working on nine projects and two internships. Seeking a software development related job to further improve and grow my career.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### **Developer & Tutorial Creator (Intern)**

Feb 2022 - Aug 2022

Blockonomics, Hyderabad (Remote)

(6 months)

- Building demonstration websites using implementations of the Blockonomics API to create developer tutorials.
- Making a video explaining the demo for YouTube tutorials.
- Writing a blog post to help developers understand how to integrate Blockonomics product's API.
- Research on new topics and creation of videos on them, such as Gap Limit / Testing.
- Technologies Used: Django, React, InShot Editor App, GIT, Postman.

# Web Developer (Intern)

Nov 2020 - Feb 2022

Korangle, Shujalpur (Remote)

(1.3 years)

- Full Stack new module implementation front-end (Angular), back-end (Django) and Designing (Figma).
- Fixing of the bugs raised by the QA Tester and clients in the software.
- Research work about the new feature requirement requested by the clients.
- Web scraping school information from websites for marketing purposes and updating it in Google Sheets using an automated approach with the use of Google APIs.
- Technologies Used: Angular, Django, WordPress, AWS EC2, GIT, Selenium, Figma.

## **EDUCATION**

**Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.) - Computer Science** 

Aug 2019 - May 2023

SRM Valliammai Engineering College, Chennai

GPA: 8.8/10

(Expected)

# **Higher Secondary - Computer Science**

Jun 2018 - Apr 2019

Sitadevi Garodia Hindu Vidyalaya, Chennai

Percentage: 84/100

High School Jun 2016 - Apr 2017

Saraswathi Matriculation School, Chennai

Percentage: 94.8/100

#### AREAS OF INTEREST

Full Stack Development, Software Development, Android Development, Artificial Intelligence, Cryptocurrency, Data Science, Internet Of Things.

## **SKILLS**

Java, Python, C, JavaScript, Angular, Django, Tomcat, AWS, MySQL, MongoDB, Full Stack Development, Android Studio, Web Development, Software Development, Backend, Frontend.

## **PROJECTS**

# Multiplayer Chess WebApp

2020

Technologies used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ¡Query, Java, MySQL and AWS.

Link: https://syedanas.com:8443/

# **Movie Rating Website**

2020

Technologies used: Angular and Django.

*Link:* https://github.com/SyedAnas26/Movie-Rating-Website-FrontEnd

# Pollify Android App

2021

Technologies used: Java, React, Django, Figma, MySQL and AWS

*Link:* https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.pollify

# **Shop the Shop Android App**

2022

Technologies used: Java , Django, Figma, MySQL

Link: https://ijcrt.org/papers/IJCRT2205804.pdf

### **Library Management Website**

2022

Technologies used: HTML, Knockout JS, Java, Tomcat, MySQL

*Link:* https://syedanas.com:8443/LibMag/

### **Cyborgs Website**

2022

Technologies used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Django, MySQL

*Link:* https://cyborgs22.com/

## **Bottle Classifier GUI App**

2022

Technologies used: PyQT5, Pyside2, Python, Matplotlib, MongoDB

*Link:* https://github.com/SyedAnas26/bottle\_classifier\_app

### **OTHER LINKS**



https://syedanas.com



https://www.linkedin.com/in/syed-anas-ahmed-826a9b1ba/



https://github.com/SyedAnas26/